{
  "isTheory": true,
  "openingRemarks": "Find the solution to the following equations",
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "\\(-(s + 4) = 18 \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n-(s + 4) &= 18 \\\\\n-s - 4 &= 18 \\\\\n-s &= 18 + 4 \\\\\n-s &= 22 \\\\\n\\dfrac{-s}{-1} &= \\dfrac{22}{-1} \\\\\ns &= -22\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = 18</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(-(s+4)\\) if \\(s=-1\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n-(s + 4) &= -(-22 + 4) \\\\\n&= -(-18) \\\\\n&= 18 \\\\\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(8 + 3(n - 9) = 17 \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n8 + 3(n - 9) &= 17 \\\\\n8 + 3n - 27 &= 17 \\\\\n3n &= 17 + 27 - 8 \\\\\n3n &= 36 \\\\\n\\dfrac{3n}{3} &= \\dfrac{36}{3} \\\\\nn &= 12\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = 17</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(8 + 3(n - 9)\\) if \\(n=12\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n8 + 3(n - 9) &= 8 + 3(12 - 9) \\\\\n&= 8 + 3(3) \\\\\n&= 8 + 9 \\\\\n&= 17\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(23 - 3(y - 7) = 8 \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n23 - 3(y - 7) &= 8 \\\\\n23 - 3y + 21 &= 8 \\\\\n-3y &= 8 - 21 - 23 \\\\\n-3y &= -36 \\\\\n\\dfrac{-3y}{-3} &= \\dfrac{-36}{-3} \\\\\ny &= 12\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = 8</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(23 - 3(y - 7)\\) if \\(y=12\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n23 - 3(y - 7) &= 23 - 3(12 - 7) \\\\\n&= 23 - 3(5) \\\\\n&= 23 - 15 \\\\\n&= 8\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(\\dfrac{1}{3}(6m + 21) = m - 7 \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n\\dfrac{1}{3}(6m + 21) &= m - 7 \\\\\n3 \\times \\dfrac{1}{3}(6m + 21) &= 3(m - 7) \\\\\n6m + 21 &= 3m - 21 \\\\\n6m - 3m &= -21 - 21 \\\\\n3m &= -42 \\\\\n\\dfrac{3m}{3} &= \\dfrac{-42}{3} \\\\\nm &= -14\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = RHS</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(\\dfrac{1}{3}(6m + 21)\\) if \\(m=-14\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n\\dfrac{1}{3}(6m + 21) &= \\dfrac{1}{3}(6(-14) + 21) \\\\\n&= \\dfrac{1}{3}(-84 + 21) \\\\\n&= \\dfrac{1}{3}(-63) \\\\\n&= -21\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n<div>Evaluate \\(m - 7\\) if \\(m=-14\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\nm - 7 &= -14 - 7 \\\\\n&= -21\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(8(r - 2) = 6(r + 10) \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n8(r - 2) &= 6(r + 10) \\\\\n8r - 16 &= 6r + 60 \\\\\n8r - 6r &= 60 + 16 \\\\\n2r = 76 \\\\\n\\dfrac{2r}{2} &= \\dfrac{76}{2} \\\\\nr &= 38\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = RHS</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(8(r - 2)\\) if \\(r=38\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n8(r - 2) &= 8(38 - 2) \\\\\n&= 8(36) \\\\\n&= 288\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n<div>Evaluate \\(6(r + 10)\\) if \\(r=38\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n6(r + 10) &= 6(38 + 10) \\\\\n&= 6(48) \\\\\n&= 288\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(5 + 7(2 - 5x) = 2(9x + 1) - (13x - 57) \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n5 + 7(2 - 5x) &= 2(9x + 1) - (13x - 57) \\\\\n5 + 14 - 35x &= 18x + 2 - 13x + 57 \\\\\n-35x - 18x + 13x &= 57 + 2 - 5 - 14 \\\\\n-40x = 40 \\\\\n\\dfrac{-40x}{-40} &= \\dfrac{40}{-40} \\\\\nx &= -1\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = RHS</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(5 + 7(2 - 5x)\\) if \\(x=-1\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n5 + 7(2 - 5x) &= 5 + 7(2 - 5(-1)) \\\\\n&= 5 + 7(2 + 5) \\\\\n&= 5 + 7(7) \\\\\n&= 5 + 49 \\\\\n&= 54\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n<div>Evaluate \\(2(9x + 1) - (13x - 57)\\) if \\(x=-1\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n2(9x + 1) - (13x - 57) &= 2(9(-1) + 1) - (13(-1) - 57) \\\\\n&= 2(-9 + 1) - (-13 - 57) \\\\\n&= 2(-8) - (-70) \\\\\n&= -16 + 70 \\\\\n&= 54\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(4(3.5y + 0.25) = 365 \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n4(3.5y + 0.25) &= 365 \\\\\n14y + 1 &= 365 \\\\\n14y &= 365 - 1 \\\\\n14y = 364 \\\\\n\\dfrac{14y}{14} &= \\dfrac{364}{14} \\\\\ny &= 26\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = 365</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(4(3.5y + 0.25)\\) if \\(y=26\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n4(3.5y + 0.25) &= 4(3.5(26) + 0.25) \\\\\n&= 4(91 + 0.25) \\\\\n&= 4(91.25) \\\\\n&= 365\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(0.25(q - 8) = 0.1(q + 7) \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n0.25(q - 8) &= 0.1(q + 7) \\\\\n0.25q - 2 &= 0.1q + 0.7 \\\\\n0.25q - 0.1q &= 0.7 + 2 \\\\\n0.15q = 2.7 \\\\\n\\dfrac{0.15q}{0.15} &= \\dfrac{2.7}{0.15} \\\\\nq &= 18\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = RHS</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(0.25(q - 8)\\) if \\(q=18\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n0.25(q - 8) &= 0.25(18 - 8) \\\\\n&= 0.25(10) \\\\\n&=2.5\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(0.1(q + 7)\\) if \\(q=18\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n0.1(q + 7) &= 0.1(18 + 7) \\\\\n&= 0.1(25) \\\\\n&=2.5\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(\\dfrac{2}{5}n - \\dfrac{1}{10} = \\dfrac{7}{10} \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n\\dfrac{2}{5}n - \\dfrac{1}{10} &= \\dfrac{7}{10} \\\\\n10 \\times \\dfrac{2}{5}n - 10 \\times \\dfrac{1}{10} &= 10 \\times \\dfrac{7}{10} \\\\\n2(2n) - 1 &= 7 \\\\\n4n = 7 + 1 \\\\\n4n &= 8 \\\\\n\\dfrac{4n}{4} &= \\dfrac{8}{4} \\\\\nn &= 2\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = \\(\\dfrac{7}{10}\\)</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(\\dfrac{2}{5}n - \\dfrac{1}{10}\\) if \\(n=2\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n\\dfrac{2}{5}n - \\dfrac{1}{10} &= \\dfrac{2}{5}(2) - \\dfrac{1}{10} \\\\\n&= \\dfrac{4}{5} - \\dfrac{1}{10} \\\\\n&=\\dfrac{7}{10}\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(\\dfrac{1}{3}x + \\dfrac{1}{5}x = 8 \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n\\dfrac{1}{3}x + \\dfrac{1}{5}x &= 8 \\\\\n15 \\times \\dfrac{1}{3}x + 15 \\times \\dfrac{1}{5}x &= 15 \\times 8 \\\\\n5x + 3x &= 120 \\\\\n8x &= 120 \\\\\n\\dfrac{8x}{8} &= \\dfrac{120}{8} \\\\\nx &= 15\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = 8</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(\\dfrac{1}{3}x + \\dfrac{1}{5}x\\) if \\(x=15\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n\\dfrac{1}{3}x + \\dfrac{1}{5}x &= \\dfrac{1}{3}(15) + \\dfrac{1}{5}(15) \\\\\n&= 5 + 3 \\\\\n&= 8\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n"
    }
  ]
}
